Contact

07517390793 (Mobile) risoknop@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/richardknop (LinkedIn)

richardknop.com/ (Personal) blog.richardknop.com/ (Blog)

Top Skills

Go

Kubernetes

Python

Languages

English

Slovak

Czech

Publications

Sorting Algorithms Primer

Richard Knop

Open Source Software Engineer

London, United Kingdom

Summary

I'm an experienced distributed systems engineer, open source contributor, Gopher and Pythonista I have mostly focused on backend programming in Go & Python, also dev ops and automation (AWS, Terraform, Ansible, docker, a bit of kubernetes).

My experience ranges from being first or one of first engineers at small startups, through working for large enterprise corporations and government agencies, to working for hyper growth startup unicorns with massive scale.

Check out my flagship open source project Machinery (long story short - celery for golang). Also see my github profile for my other contributions.

https://github.com/RichardKnop/machinery https://github.com/RichardKnop

Experience

Grab

Senior Software Development Engineer January 2018 - January 2019 (1 year 1 month) Singapore

As part of DAX Experience team, I am working on maintaining and improving existing critical services for the driver mobile app (50k QPS).

In addition, I am writing micro services to support new business requirements as well as decouple and refactor old monolithic services to make the overall platform less brittle, easier to test and more robust overall.

Technologies used include: Golang, Redis, MySQL, Jenkins, AWS, HTTP, gRPC, protocol buffers (protobuf), circuit breakers, microservices

Apollo Labs Ltd
Contract Software Engineer
June 2014 - October 2017 (3 years 5 months)
London, Greater London, United Kingdom

I have worked as a contract software engineer through my own private ltd company.

This includes several clients such as Sony PlayStation, Government Digital Service, Cancer Research UK, Sainsbury's and others.

Most of the roles were mostly based on Golang programming but there was also a mix of dev ops work with tools such as AWS, docker, Terraform, Ansible and a bit of Kubernetes, Cloudfoundry and Tsuru.

YOU Technologies Group Limited Senior Software Engineer August 2016 - March 2017 (8 months) Hong Kong

I was working on API platform for a new digital bank, integrating with third party banking APIs (payment processors, forex vendors etc), also doing some dev ops & automation.

Technologies used include: Golang, Kubernetes, Terraform, Ansible, AWS, etcd, Docker, NATS

Yoyo Wallet Software Engineer January 2014 - June 2014 (6 months)

As a first backend engineer I have written the entire original API and web services that powered the mobile app and ePOS integration.

I was responsible for delivering major components of the next version of the web and mobile platform that included: payment processing, loyalty and rewards, data analytics, campaign management, as well as ensuring the backend platform supports these tools and others.

Technologies used include: Python, Django, RabbitMQ, Celery, Postgres, DynamoDB, Memcache, Puppet, AWS

Hailo

Senior Web Developer September 2013 - January 2014 (5 months)

I worked as full stack engineer across both back end and front end. As part of the Wallet team I was responsible for maintaining legacy platform as well as developing services and UIs for the new generation platform's payment system.

Technologies used include: Go, Cassandra, JavaScript, BackBone, EmberJS, HTML5, CSS, SASS

Brave Bison Senior Developer February 2013 - September 2013 (8 months) London, United Kingdom

I worked on several RIA apps such as HTML5 player used to stream London Fashion Week and backend APIs for the platform to manage the video streaming content.

Technologies used include: JavaScript, Backbone, RequireJS, QUnit, PhantomJS, Selenium, HTML5, CSS, SASS, Compass, Jenkins, AWS

Saffron Digital
Web Services Developer
November 2011 - February 2013 (1 year 4 months)

As a web services developer my first job was to add new features, maintain and fix bugs on the HTC Watch backend. This included lots of refactoring of existing APIs, increasing test coverage and introduction of continuous integration.

After tackling HTC Watch I worked on several new generation services such as payment service (supporting support for debit / credit cards, carrier billing and vouchers), video transcoding service (using mainly ffmpeg but also other open source transcoding libraries), key delivery service for DRM or the locker service.

All of these web services would become the next generation platform called Nexus which has been a great success and is being used until this day (with almost zero downtime since its inception).

Other than writing web services I also did a lot of devops work like writing Puppet manifests and modules to automate configuration of servers and reliable deployment and scaling of services. I also briefly joined the KDDI Video Pass team and helped with the HTML5 web app.

Technologies used include: Python, Django, MySQL, DynamoDB, Puppet, AWS, Jenkins, ffmpeg

Education

The Technical University of Košice

Bc. (Bachelor's degree), Cybernetics / Artificial Intelligence · (2007 - 2010)

Evanjelické gymnázium J. A. Komenského School leaving exams · (1999 - 2007)